And welcome back to our challenge again.
다시 도전 과제를 시작하죠
And this time we are working with our beautiful prototype.
이번에는 아름다운 프로토타입을 준비했어요
Uh, with this time the default set to the Python Hard challenge rather than the simple pi code.
이번에는 파이썬 하드 챌린지로 기본 설정합니다 간단한 파이 코드보다는요
We bring this up.
이걸 꺼내요
Here it is.
여기 있네요
We're going to kick off the Python run, which you may remember takes about 2720 eight seconds.
파이썬 실행을 시작하겠습니다 기억하실지 모르겠지만 2720 8초가 걸리죠
So we'll be sitting here for a little while.
여기 좀 앉아 있어야겠어요
While that runs, I am then going to do use GPT to convert the code to C plus plus and run that.
실행되는 동안 GPT를 이용해 코드를 C++로 변환하고 실행할게요
And then we'll do the same with Claude and see how Claude fares and see if there are any differences
클로드가 어떻게 하는지 보고 지난번과 다른 점이
from last time.
있는지 보죠
Uh, almost there.
거의 다 왔어요
You can watch Gradio gives us a little timer, which is very handy in these situations.
그라디오가 타이머를 주는 걸 보세요 이런 상황에서 아주 편리하죠
So we'll know that there we go.
알게 될 겁니다 됐어요
We get the answer that is the right answer.
Get it, get it, get it, get it, get it, get it, get it, get it, get it, get, get 정답, 정답이 나왔어요
And it took about 28 seconds.
28초 정도 걸렸어요
All right.
좋아요
We asked GPT to convert this into C plus plus code.
GPT에 이걸 C 플러스 플러스 코드로 변환하라고 했어요
Here is the C plus plus code.
C 플러스 플러스 코드예요
There is the result.
결과가 나왔네요
And we will then run that C plus plus code.
그런 다음 C++ 코드를 실행하죠
And it has the same problem as before.
예전과 같은 문제가 있어요
There's I believe it's a number overflow that's resulting in the answer being zero and not even that
숫자가 넘쳐나서 답이 0이 된 것 같아요 그렇게 빠르지도 않고요
quick.
왜냐하면 그 답에 0을 주는데 중첩된 루프도 발생하거든요
Let's see how Claude fares.
클로드가 어떻게 하는지 보죠
We switch to Claude, we convert the code.
클로드로 바꿔서 코드를 변환해요
Here we go.
시작할게요
Let's see what Claude has done.
클로드가 뭘 했는지 보러 가요
Aha!
네
Interestingly, this time Claude has not seen that it can do the single loop.
흥미롭게도 클로드는 단일 회전을 할 수 있다는 걸 못 봤어요
So we've got a different answer from Claude this time.
클로드의 대답이 이번에는 달라요
There we go.
됐어요
We'll see how Claude does if its code runs.
코드가 작동하는지 클로드가 어떻게 하는지 보죠
At least let's run that C plus.
C 플러스라도 해 보죠
Plus it got the right answer and it took 0.6 seconds.
게다가 정답도 맞혔고 0점이었어요 6초요
So Claude at least gets the right answer.
클로드가 정답을 맞혔네요
But it is not this time.
이번엔 아니에요
This time that we ran with Claude.
이번에는 클로드와 달렸죠
It didn't crush it like last time, because it didn't actually spot that opportunity to to to collapse
지난번처럼 실패하진 않았어요 캐논 알고리즘을 이용해 루프를 무너뜨릴 기회를
the loop using Canon's algorithm.
포착하지 못했거든요
And now remember it's called.
이 요리의 이름을 기억하세요
So I guess we can try one more time converting the code and see if it if it gets it on a second attempt.
코드를 한 번 더 변환해 두 번째 시도에 성공하는지 보죠
Let's see.
어디 보죠
Let's see, let's see.
어디 봐요
That does look like it's one loop doesn't it.
한 바퀴 도는 것 같죠?
All right.
좋아요
Let's let's see if it's, uh, that's going to work for us.
이 정도면 될지 보죠
It did work.
효과가 있었어요
Second time lucky.
두 번째는 운이 좋았어요
We get the right answer.
Get it, Get it 정답이 나오죠
And again we have that breathtaking.
숨막히게 아름다운 장면이죠
Oh my goodness.
말도 안 돼요
It's a whole lot better than last time as well.
지난번보다 훨씬 나아요
Obviously there's some, uh, dependency on what else is running on on my processor.
제 프로세서에 실행되는 다른 것들에 의존성이 있어요
We're probably down to the sort of the noise levels, but that is 0.4 of a, uh, of a millisecond,
소음 수준으로 떨어졌지만 0이에요 4분의 1초요, 비교하면...
uh, compared to, uh, let's do the maths one more time.
계산을 다시 해 보죠
It's embarrassing that I can't do these sort of orders of magnitude in my head, but I'm too afraid
머리로 규모를 계산할 수 없다는 게 부끄럽지만 너무 많이 계산하지 않을까
that I'll get off by by too much.
봐 두려워요. Get it.
28.3 divided by 0.000446.
28살요 3 나누기 0은요? 000446년요
Uh, it's more than 60,000 times faster.
60,000배 이상 빨라요
Uh, which, of course, is not that surprising given that it's found an algorithm that involves a single
물론 그리 놀라운 일은 아니죠 중첩된 루프가 아닌 싱글 루프를
loop rather than a nested loop, but it is great to see that.
포함한 알고리즘을 찾았으니까요 하지만 보기 좋네요
So in summary, Claude managed to to to work where GPT four failed.
요약하자면 클로드는 GPT 4가 실패한 일을 해냈죠
And Claude sometimes not always, is breathtakingly faster.
클로드는 항상 빠른 건 아니지만 가끔은 엄청나게 빨라요
Breathtaking, I will say, from doing my experiments that there were a couple of occasions when Claude
숨이 막힐 정도로요 실험을 하면서 클로드가 회전하는 숫자를
also made a mistake with the number rounding and and both Claude and GPT four zero got zero.
틀리는 경우가 몇 번 있었어요 클로드와 GPT 40 둘 다 0이 나왔죠
But GPT four zero seems to consistently make that mistake.
GPT 40은 계속 그런 실수를 반복하는 것 같아요
And more often than not, Claude not only gets it right, but also spots this opportunity to rewrite
클로드는 종종 그걸 제대로 해낼 뿐 아니라 알고리즘을 다시 쓸 기회를 포착해
the algorithm and be staggeringly faster.
놀랍도록 빠르게 만들죠
So I think, again, I double down and say, this is a victory for Claude.
그래서 전 다시 강조해요 클로드의 승리라고요
Um, and then next week we are going to switch to open source.
다음 주에는 오픈 소스로 전환할 거예요
We're going to assess open source models.
오픈 소스 모델을 평가할 거예요
We're going to see how open source models generate code and use a solution with open source Llms.
오픈 소스 모델이 어떻게 코드를 생성하고 오픈 소스 LMS 솔루션을 사용하는지 보죠
The question will be can open source compete with Claude?
오픈 소스가 클로드와 경쟁할 수 있을까요?
3.5 sonnet.
3번요 5 소네트요
Uh, with this astoundingly fast, uh, result.
이렇게 놀라울 정도로 빠른 결과로요
See you then.
그때 봐요